

### **Contact**



+54 9 0-3446 15-521419



eichhorn.gustavof@gmail.com



Buenos Aires, Argentine.

## **Social Media**



https://www.linkedin.com/in/gustavo-francisco-eichhorn/



https://www.facebook.com/gustavo.eichhorn



https://gustavo-feichhorn.netlify.app/

### Skills

# **Hobbies**









# **Gustavo Francisco Eichhorn**

# Mechanical Engineer

"Mechanical Engineer with over 14 years of experience in researching and solving complex technical problems in the nuclear energy and space technology industries. My skills include creating 3D models, finite element simulations, handling software such as Autodesk Inventor, Solidworks, ANSYS, and Matlab. I have led various projects, from instrumentation and control assembly to procurement management and the manufacturing of composite material tubes (filament winding). I am focused on continuing my professional growth, bringing my experience to innovative projects, and taking on new challenges."

### **Work Experience:**

Comisión Nacional of Athomik Energy, From 03/11/2014 to present. Sr. Mechanical Engineer.

Mechanical Engineer belonging to the MGSE Group (Mechanical Ground Support Equipment) belonging to the A.R.A.S Project. (Synthetic Aperture Radar Antenna) of the SAOCOM satellite. Design and structural calculation tasks in the Composite Materials Technology Department belonging to the Technological Development and Special Projects Management.

- Creation of 3D solid models in collaboration with other work groups using Solidedge, SolidWorks, or Inventor.
- Conducting simulations using finite elements with <u>ANSYS</u> and FEMAP.
- Calculations and verifications using <u>Matlab</u>, <u>Simulink and Python</u>.
- Generating documentation such as plans, technical specifications for purchases, service instructions, etc.
- Participating in the procurement of devices through a bidding or price competition system.
- Interaction with equipment manufacturers. Conducting scheduled visits to workshops.
- Operation of MGSEs: handling of panels for work or preparation for transport.
- Assembly of the G-Negator system for antenna deployment testing.
- Participation in wing integration activities at the <u>CEATSA</u> (INVAP) facilities in Bariloche, Argentina.
- Involvement in product quality assurance reports, lessons learned, and EIDPs.
- Manufacturing of carbon fiber-epoxy tubes using Filament-Winding.
- Conducting a service inspection report for the CAREM-25 project using ASME standards, presented to the IAEA (https://lnkd.in/dF9jav5r).

#### Nucleoeléctrica S.A.

From 01/07/2010 to 30/10/2010. Jr. Mechanical Engineer.

I worked in the instrumentation and control area of CNA 2 (<u>Atucha 2 Nuclear Power Station</u>). In it I was in charge of the transfer of Instrumentation and control cabinets to the start-up sector of the plant and their verification and inspection. I was also in charge of the group in charge of the assembly of instrumentation of the fuel element recharging machine of the plant and I was part of the group of assembly and inspection of instrumentation belonging to its tilting bottle and the transfer channel.

- Creation of detailed plans for the assembly of equipment and instruments.
- On-site inspections to subsequently create power and instrumentation/control wiring diagrams.
- Supervision of personnel to carry out assembly, wiring, and connection tasks.
  Coordination of tasks.
- Attendance at coordination meetings for plant-wide activities.
- Review of stock in warehouses.
- Preparation of technical specifications for purchases using the SAP system.
- Transfer of systems to Commissioning.
- Inspection of control room cabinets.
- Creation of Non-Conformity reports.

### **Education**

Magister in Cience and Tecnology of Materials.

Instituto Sábato. From 2019 to present (Tesis finished).

#### Mechanical Engineer.

Universidad Nacional de La Plata. 2005-2012 (Final Project).